拿好 这是中毒抢救中心的电话
Okay, here's the number for poison control.
找卡罗就行了
Ask for Carol.
宝贝 我们没问题的
Honey, we're gonna be fine.
好好享受同学聚会去吧
Enjoy your reunion.
如果你能一起去的话就更好了
Oh, it'd be a lot more fun if you were there.
真抱歉我去不了
I really am sorry about that.
我不能错过和杰同队打保龄球的机会
I just can't miss the chance to bowl on Jay's team.
所以我才买了这双极速滑翔鞋
That's why I ordered these glide rights.
只要你穿法正确 这双鞋能带给你
If you break'em in properly, they're supposed to give you
毫无阻力的滑行
a completely frictionless--
老实说 如果菲尔不去的话
If I'm being honest, the reunion might be a little more fun
同学聚会才会更好玩
if Phil isn't there.
否则 我整个周末都得给他介绍谁是谁
Otherwise, I spend the whole weekend telling him who's who
解释他听不懂的小圈子笑话
and explaining inside jokes.
如果我的时间都用来给他解释
And if all that explaining is going out,
就没时间喝酒了
the alcohol is not going in.
妈 你走之前得签一下学校的这张表
Hey, mom. Before you go, you have to sign this for school.
不用看了 都是些套话
You don't have to read it. It's all boilerplate.
宝贝 我要迟到了 让你爸签吧
Honey, I am running really late. Ask your dad.
老爸在这儿呢
Right here, buddy.
我擦
S--uhh!
我得找家长签字
I have to get the letter signed
是因为我的《美国革命战争》作业不合格
because I failed my assignment on the Revolutionary War.
我重现了邦克山战役
I recreated the battle of Bunker Hill
用了以前的科学实验模型
using one of my old science projects.
在我看来这挺有"革命性"的啊
Seemed pretty revolutionary to me.
勇敢的爱国者们攀登高山
The brave patriots made their way up the hillside,
准备好了迎战狡诈的英国红衫军
prepared for whatever the devious Red Coats might inflict next.
这回你倒喷发了
Now you work?!
-爸... -稍等 老弟
- So, dad... - One second, buddy.
卖鞋的说 当你开始适应这种鞋
The salesman said when you're breaking these shoes in,
左右移动会变得更容易
it's easier to move side to side.
好家伙
Son of a gun.
他说得对啊
He was right.
要我签什么
What do we got here?
我等这一天等了一年了
I've waited a year for this day--
一年一度的同行工会保龄球锦标赛
The annual trade association scratch bowling tournament.
去年 我们输给了最强的对手
Last year, we lost to our biggest rival.
弗雷泽有劲敌阿里
Frazier had Ali.
"普里契特衣柜队"有"衣柜衣柜衣柜衣柜队"
Pritchett's Closets has Closets, Closets, Closets, Closets.
他们名字很傻 但球技不容小觑
It's a stupid name, but those cats can bowl.
我就知道 你闻到煎饼味就会下来
Ay, I knew the pancakes would bring you down.
今天只喝咖啡好了
Just coffee for me today.
黑咖啡 正如我的心情一般黑暗
Black, like I feel on the inside.
曼尼 拜托 只是一次试唱失败而已
Ay, Manny. Please, it was only one bad audition.
不 是三次试唱失败
No, three bad auditions--
秋季汇演 《歌剧魅影》
Fall Assembly, "Phantom,"
以及这回的春季歌唱节
and now the Spring Sing.
我弱爆了
I'm a disaster.
你总是这么夸张
You're always so dramatic.
你说我夸张吗 妈妈
Dramatic, mother?
我相信小卡今天就会打来
I am sure that Cam is gonna call you today
把独唱部分安排给你的
and give you the solo.
你对自己要求太严苛了
You're always so hard on yourself.
还记得你说过你的脸型不适合戴帽子吗
Remember that you said that you didn't have a face for hats?
-结果呢 -我戴什么帽子都好看
- And? - I look great in every hat.
我听不到
I can't hear you.
我戴什么帽子都好看
I look great in every hat.
趁好看的时候好好臭美吧
Well, enjoy that while it lasts.
我曾以为自己戴帽子很好看
I had a pretty good hat run,
但后来看到一张在农场度假时拍的照片
but then I saw a photo of myself from the dude ranch.
看着就像格莱美上的瑞芭一样奇葩
I looked like Reba at the Grammys.
看来你找到皮草了
I see that you found the fur.
是的 对了 你有羽毛围脖吗
Yes. Uh, you wouldn't happen to have a feather boa, would you?
你要在你们的奥斯卡派对上戴吗
Are you wearing that to your Oscar Party?
不是的 曼尼 我们才没那么俗气
No, Manny. We're not cliches.
小卡在做派对布置
Cam's decorating the party
用莉莉打扮成各个明星的照片来...
with photos of Lily dressed as different starlets from the--
好吧 我们的确俗气
W-we--we're cliches.
歌洛莉亚
Hey, Gloria,
看我在保龄球包里找到了什么
look what I found in my bowling bag.
去年锦标赛的二等奖
Second place prize in last year's tournament--
免费水疗
A spa day.
但过了今天就作废了
Oh, but it expires today.
不好意思
Oh. Sorry.
我真希望能用上
I just wish that I could use this.
但是今天保姆放假了
But today's the nanny's day off,
我有一大堆的事情要做
and I have a million things to do.
我得去买尿布 取婴儿车
I have to buy diapers, I have to go pick up the stroller,
我还得去看医生
I have to go to the doctor.
我真不想浪费掉 可是
I hate wasting this, but...
我今天真的没时间
I just don't have any time today.
是的 其实我很想去做水疗
Yes, I would have loved to go to the spa,
但自从我生了孩子
but having a baby has changed completely
杰全家人对我的看法完全变了
the way that Jay's family look at me.
我不再是只会去做头发的歌洛莉亚
I am not anymore just Gloria that has her hair done,
只会去健身的歌洛莉亚
Gloria that goes to the gym.
现在我是新妈歌洛莉亚
Now I am Gloria the new mother--
让人惊呼"真不知她是如何办到的"的女人
the "I don't know how she does it" lady.
如果羽毛围脖不在这儿
If the feather boa is not here,
就是在我表妹那儿
it's at my cousin's.
等我看完医生买完药 去婴儿用品店前
I will go get it after the doctor, after the pharmacy,
就去帮你拿 好吗
before the baby store, okay?
说真的 歌洛莉亚
Honestly, Gloria,
我真不知道你是如何办到的
I don't know how you do it.
找到啦
Ah, found it!
-扶我一把 -小心点儿
- Help me. - Careful.
歌洛莉亚 你没事吧
Oh, Gloria! Are you all right?
我说了叫你扶我一把
Ay, I told you to help me!
-真对不起 -我扭到脚了
- I am so sorry! - I twisted my ankle.
来 坐这里
Okay. Sit down right here.
我没时间坐着了
I don't have time for this.
不行 你不能这样走一整天啊
No, you--you can't walk around on that all day.
不 我没事 我没事
No, I'm good. I'm good.
没事 我会用
No. I will use...
婴儿车当拐杖的 行不
the baby carrier as a... as a cane. Okay?
行吧
O-okay.
保持住 就那样 好的 好的
Now hold that. Hold that. Good, good, good.
表情忧郁点 忧郁
Now smolder. Smolder.
完美 太好了
Perfect. Perfect.
我猜猜看
Let me guess--
你忘了我说的是"围脖"还是"宝宝"
You couldn't remember if I said "Boa" or "Baby,"
所以干脆两样都带回来了
so you brought both.
歌洛莉亚受伤了
Gloria hurt herself,
有我的责任 所以我主动提出照看乔
and it was kinda my fault, so I offered to watch Joe.
我休息一下可以吗 我想一个人待会儿
Can I take a break? I wanna be alone.
扮葛丽泰·嘉宝时你怎么没这股酷劲儿
Okay, where was that attitude when we were doing Greta Garbo?
好吧 休息5分钟
Okay, fine. Take five.
你好啊 小乔乔
Hi, baby Joe.
你要不要来坐一会儿呢
Why don't you just sit a spell?
我们正在拍照照哦
We're just makin' pictures.
-干嘛用密苏里州口音 -不知道
- Why are you being all Missouri? - I don't know.
大概是要回农场太兴奋了吧
I guess I'm excited to go back to the farm.
有那么明显吗
Is it that obvious?
你吃早饭时候说了"该屎"这个词
You said "dagburn" at breakfast.
你给我们订机票了没
Have you booked our tickets yet?
我不确定上班时能不能走得开
You know, I-I'm not sure if I can get off work.
好吧 但你得趁早订到票
Yeah, but you have to get the tickets
不然好座位都被抢光了
before all the good seats are taken.
你是说那些不飞往密苏里的航班吧
You mean the ones that aren't on a plane to Missouri?
好了 亲爱的 休息时间结束
Okay, sweetie, break's over.
还没到5分钟呢
It hasn't been five minutes.
是的 但你都吃掉5块动物饼干了
Yes, but it has been five animal crackers.
按规定在拍摄日是一块都不能吃的 所以...
Which is five too many to eat on a shoot day. So...
受够了 我不干了
No more! I quit!
我的天呐 她这是鬼上身了吗
Oh, my gosh. What has gotten into her?
我们拍了6个小时
We've been doing this for six hours,
怎么突然之间 她就不爱玩了呢
and now all of the sudden, she doesn't love it?
我一直有种看法
You know, I have a theory.
好吧
Okay.
我想拍的照片
Well, we're only halfway through
刚刚拍完一半
all the pictures that I wanted to do.
灵光一现 你好啊 小乔乔
Lightbulb. Hello, baby Joe!
你甚至可以扮作
Well, you may as well be
暴风雨过后小镇树林里的死流浪汉
a dead hobo in the woods of a small town after a rainstorm,
因为你被我这个大星探发现咯
because you have just been discovered.
我真是对密苏里州之行越来越没兴趣了
I'm looking less and less forward to this trip to Missouri.
你好 帅哥
Hey, handsome.
你能不能在这上面签个字 不用看的
Uh, can you sign this? You don't need to read it.
从来不看
Never do!
就在这儿
Right there.
快问快答 大自然的高效晒后修复品是
Oh. Quick--nature's sure-fire sunburn remedy?
"芦喂"[芦荟+喂]
Aloe?
杰 想到我们的大赛我就超兴奋呐
Hey, Jay. Super excited about our big match.
我昨天晚上梦到比赛了
I dreamt about it last night.
你猜怎么着 我们赢了
Guess what? We won!
菲尔 我太爱你了就不跟你
Phil, I like you too much to sugarcoat
拐弯抹角的了 你被队里开除了
what I'm about to say-- you're off the team.
有意思 用幽默让我在赛前放松
Good one. Loosen me up with some pre-match humor.
我喜欢
I like it.
不是 我找到更好的选手了 卢迪·索伦孙
Nah, I found somebody better-- Rudy Sorrenson.
他参赛 你退出
He's in, you're out.
好笑
Hilarious!
坚持不懈啊
Stickin' with the bit.
我们俩变得这么亲密无间真让我高兴
I love that this is our relationship now.
这场比赛关系重大 你的发挥又不稳定
This match is too important, and you're a wild card.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
杰
Jay...
我不喜欢你现在跟我来这么一出
I'm not sure I like where this is headed.
菲尔 不是针对你 只是个保龄球赛
Phil, this is nothing personal. It's bowling.
没关系 我明白
No, no, no. I get it.
听着 我得挂了
Listen, um... I should get goin'.
我的过敏症让我快要流泪了
My allergies are starting to cry.
喂 歌洛莉亚 我就要出发了
Hey, Gloria. I was just about to leave.
什么事
What's up?
曼尼刚给我发了短信 他跟你说了没
Manny just texted me. Did he tell you the news?
说了 太好了 我们晚点再庆祝
Yes. Wonderful. We'll celebrate later.
不 他没得到独唱的机会
No. He didn't get the solo.
他好像非常难过
I think he's very upset.
手套没拿
My glove.
你在哪里
Where are you?
在看医生 他在为我检查脚踝
At the doctor. He's checking my ankle.
杰 我觉得你应该去安慰他一下
Jay, I think you should try to cheer him up.
你何不带他去逛逛街呢
Why don't you take him shopping?
歌洛莉亚 我5点钟比赛
Gloria, my match is at 5:00.
我还有仪式要做
I have a ritual.
我得走走球道 还要打两三场热身赛
I walk the lanes. I play two or three warm-up games.
他没事的 我让他跟你说
He's fine. I'll let you talk to him.
保持黑暗 拜托
Darkness, please.
糟糕 他在外面游泳呢
Aw, shoot. He's out in the pool.
我怎样才能让你离开呢 唱歌吗
What do I have to do to make you go away? Sing?
我会让他给你回电的
Uh, I'll have him call you back.
我的生活是没有音乐的灰色地狱
My life is a music-less, gray hellscape.
看你这样子
Wow. Well, this doesn't look
就算带你去逛街也没用吧
like anything shopping can help you with.
值得一试
It's worth a shot.
抱歉我刚才犹豫不决的
Sorry I was so indecisive back there.
我今天状态不好
I'm out of it today.
你买到你想要的了
Well, you got what you want,
今天的任务完成了
and that's what today is all about.
别皱眉了 笑一个
Turn that frown upside-down.
你坐15号线回家吧
Now you're gonna take this 15 local to get home.
双手抓紧那袋子
Keep both your hands tight on that bag
那趟公交途经的几个街区不太安全
because it goes through a few sketchy blocks.
你不载我回去吗
You're not driving me?
你把原本可以载你的时间都浪费于
Well, you kinda used up your drive time
在一堆同样的皮带里挑选了
deciding between those identical belts.
好吧 我只是难以接受 杰
Okay. It's just hard. You know, Jay?
我从来都不是一个轻言放弃的人
I mean, I've never been a quitter.
你的生活将开启新的篇章 有零钱没
Well, new chapter for you. You got any change?
一直以来 我都梦想成为一名演员
I mean, I always imagined I'd be a performer for life.
大概有些梦想是不得不放弃的
I guess some dreams you just have to give up on.
适时放弃才是好小伙
Know when to fold 'em.
这是50块 会有人有零钱的
Here's a $50. Someone will have change.
我唱歌不行 就是这样
I can't sing, period.
我真是老糊涂了
What am I thinking?
11号线就经过家门口 车来了
The 11 goes right by the house, and there she is.
到家了给你妈发个短信
Now text your mom when you get home.
祝你打保龄好运
Good luck with your bowling!
谢了 孩子
Thanks, kid!
对 对
Yes. Yes!
我爹的娃刚在我们这儿待了45分钟
We've had my dad's baby for 45 minutes,
就已经被穿上裙子了
and he's already in a dress.
好了 莉莉 我们的重头戏可以上了
Okay, Lily, I think we're ready for our most important setup--
-秀兰·邓波儿小姐 -给你
- Miss Shirley Temple. - Here.
你真是个好助理 胜过当模特哦
Oh, wow. You're an even better assistant than you are a model.
我不在乎
I don't care.
好吧 她还是当模特时那股冷漠劲儿
Okay, well, that came through in her modeling.
她可是我们的女儿
Our daughter.
我知道 我只是有些伤心 米奇尔
Okay, I know, but it just hurts, Mitchell.
那是她长大后抛弃的第一个我们的喜好
It's the first one of our things that she's outgrown.
但我们把她培养得有自己的
Well, you know, but isn't it great that we've raised her
想法和爱好 难道不好吗
to have opinions and interests of her own?
但要这么早吗 她还"恁"小呢
But this early? She's still so daggum young.
这又是什么南方方言
Okay, is that another southern thing,
还是你在回忆她的越南名字
or are you just trying to remember her Vietnamese name?
我的神啊 这玩意儿卡住了
Oh, my gosh. This thing is stuck.
什么 怎么会呢
What? How--how could it be?
-卡住了 -天啊
- It is stuck. - Oh!
我用胶水粘的
I glued it.
你 你为什么要那么做
W-w-why--why would you do that?
因为这珍·克罗弗德假发总是往下掉
Because the Jane Crawford wig kept falling off him.
是琼·克罗弗德
It's Joan Crawford.
你真分得清轻重缓急
'cause that's what's important here.
-好吧 -粘到他自己的头发上了
- Okay. - It's--it's glued to his actual hair.
好吧 莉莉
Okay, Lily,
这种行为很恶劣 非常恶劣
This is bad. This is very, very bad.
对不起 我只是想帮忙
Sorry. I was trying to help.
好吧 我应该料到的
Okay. Well, I should've seen this coming.
我用一个更年轻的模特取代了她
I replaced her with somebody younger,
她纯粹是因为嫉妒 搞砸了乔的拍摄
and she sabotaged Joe's shoot out of sheer jealousy.
也许她真有当模特的天分
Maybe she does have what it takes to be a model.
你能...
Can you...
-唱歌 -什么
- Sing! - What?
我听过你洗澡的时候唱歌
I've heard you sing in the shower.
你坐我车的时候也唱过 你从没跑调过
You sing in the car with me. You never miss a note!
你的症结在于不能在别人面前唱 唱啊
Your problem is doing it around people. Sing!
-你要我现在唱 -对
- You want me to sing now? - Yeah!
那都是你思想在掌控
It's all in your head!
只要你克服怯场
When you get over that little stage fright,
就再也不会在试音时卡壳了 唱啊
you'll never choke an audition again. Sing!
*傀儡 乞丐*
*I've been a puppet, a pauper*
-*海盗 诗人* -那不叫唱歌
- *a pirate, a poet* - That's not singing!
-放开唱 -*人质 国王*
- Attack it! - *a pawn and a king*
*起起伏伏 跌跌宕宕*
*I've been up and down and over and out*
*我总铭记一事*
*And I know one thing*
什么事
What's that thing?!
*每次摔得*
*Each time I find myself*
-*灰头土脸* -对 你做到了
- *flat on my face* - Yeah! Now you got it!
*我都会重新爬起*
*I pick myself up*
伸进购物袋取出帽子吧 我知道你想那么做
Get in that bag! I know you want to!
*回归到行列*
*and get back in the race*
-对 -*所谓生活*
- Yeah! - *That's life*
-*所谓生活* -唱给我听 宝贝
- *That's life* - Sing it to me, baby!
*正如人们平常所说*
*That's what all the people say*
我的天啊 那是珍妮·吉布斯吗
Oh, my god. Is that Janie Gibbs?
天啊 她的皮肤看上去像
Yikes. Her skin looks like
被重新弄平准备再利用的皱巴巴的锡纸
crumpled tinfoil you try to smooth out and use again.
提醒我千万不能在你面前显现老态
Remind me not to get old in front of you.
我甚至见不着孩子们的面了
I don't even see the kids' faces anymore.
我靠他们笔记本上的贴画来认人
I know them by the decals on their laptops.
库克教授
Professor Cooke.
依旧是校园里最性感的男人
Still the sexiest man on campus.
-想知道个小秘密吗 -你跟他约会过
- Wanna know a little somethin'? - You dated him.
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
我们一直小心保守秘密
We were so careful with that secret.
你有天穿了件大号的粗呢夹克去吃早餐
You wore an oversized tweed jacket to breakfast
还管我的兔子叫可转变的资本家
and called my rabbit convertible "Bourgeois."
确实是啊
Well, it kinda was.
我们都好嫉妒你
We were so jealous of you.
他好性感
He was so hot.
穿着海豚短裤在校园里慢跑
Jogging around campus in those dolphin shorts.
那不是我和他在一起的原因
And that wasn't even why I was with him.
我是看上了他的聪明才智
It was his mind.
你知道有些人
Do you know those people
光是在他们周围就会让人觉得
who make you feel smart
自己也变聪慧了
just by being near them?
有次我看到你们做了
I watched you guys once.
克莱尔
Claire!
克莱尔的朋友
Claire's friend!
他居然记得我
He remembers me.
你好 教授
Hello, professor.
见到你真好
It's so good to see you.
显然 学术生活很适合你
Clearly, the academic life agrees with you.
看来我们都混得不错
Oh, I guess we're all doing pretty well.
-干杯 -干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
我也在默默看着你呢
Here's lookin' at you, too.
你那时也老这样吗
Were you always like this?
克莱尔
Claire?
我的天呐 怎么可能
Oh, my God. No way.
土杜 我的上帝
Tater! Oh, my gosh! Aah!
听说你混得相当不错
I heard you're hugely successful.
还行吧 你们美女都喊我"土豆"了
Yeah, well, you know, when all the hot girls call you "Tater,"
我怎么也得努把力
You tend to try a little harder.
真可爱 你真可爱
Adorable. Adorable!
-你太可爱了 -克莱尔
- You're adorable! - Claire!
亲爱的 好啊
Honey! Hey!
菲尔 你来干什么
Hi, Phil! What are you doing here?
你爸不让我参加他的保龄球赛了
Uh... Your dad dumped me from his bowling team,
所以我就来给你个惊喜
So I thought I'd surprise you.
好吧 过来一下
Okay. Wait. Come here a second.
我 我以为你看见我会很开心呢
I-I thought you'd be happy to see me.
我开心啊 真的
I am! No, I am!
我很开心
I am happy.
出什么事了吗
Is something wrong?
就是 就是会有点尴尬
It's just-- it's a little bit embarrassing.
我的前男友也在这儿 所以...
The guy that I dated right before you is here, so...
那也没什么好尴尬的啊
Oh. Well, that's nothing to be embarrassed about.
谁没有旧爱啊
We all have exes.
你在遇到我之前甩掉的男人在这儿
So the guy you dumped right before you met me is here.
没什么大不了啊
No big deal.
其实嘛...
Well...
是他甩的我
He might've dumped me.
你不是说从来都是你甩别人吗
I thought you said you'd never been dumped.
其实嘛...就有一次
Well...Maybe one time.
那...他甩了你
So...He dumped you,
你情伤痊愈后就遇到了我
You healed completely, and then you met me.
其实嘛...
Well...
我扔过一些比克莱尔差劲很多的东西都深感后悔
I've regretted throwing away things way more beaten up than Claire.
如果那个校园花花公子想和她重修旧好
So if this campus Casanova had thoughts of reclaiming her,
猜猜怎么着 万人迷
Guess what, hot shot?
法律上来说 她仍然是我的
Legally, I still own her.
伙计 我总是在想谁这么有福气
Man, I always wondered who'd be lucky enough
会把大美人克莱尔·普里契特娶回家
to marry the beautiful Claire Pritchett.
跟运气不沾边 小伙
No luck involved, hombre.
她遇见我 爱上我
She saw, she liked,
怀了我的娃 非我不嫁
she got pregnant, she had to.
好啦 别霸占着他了
Hey! Stop hogging this guy.
我们都20年没见面了
I haven't seen him in 20 years.
我的土杜
My Tater.
我得走了
Look, I've gotta run,
但我很想请你们去我家玩玩
But I'd love to have you guys by my apartment
喝杯餐前鸡尾酒
for a cocktail before dinner.
我们当然会去
Oh! We are totally doing that.
我们可能得回宾馆...
Oh. We might have to go back to the hotel--
不不不 这周末我们就是来玩的嘛
No, no, no. Ah, that's what this weekend's for.
尽情欢笑 认识新朋友
Having a laugh, meetin' new people.
我可一点都不想错过
I don't want to miss any of it.
我可不会错过什么[警惕]
And I don't miss much.
快关门 蒸汽都跑出去了
Close the door! You're letting the steam out!
那假发摘下来了吗
Is the wig coming loose?
是啊 米奇尔 早就摘下来了
Oh, yes, Mitchell. It's completely off his head.
我们在里面待这么半天
We're just staying in here
只因为我们大丈夫和小宝贝
because there's nothing babies and big guys love more
纯粹喜欢蒸桑拿
than 100% humidity.
我的上帝
Oh, my God.
歌洛莉亚看见了会怎么修理我啊
Do you realize what Gloria's gonna do when she sees this?
上次我给曼尼画了个印度彩绘 她都揍了我一顿
She punched me when I got Manny that henna tattoo.
不是我平常那种轻轻打
And not the side-of-the-hand way that I do it.
是戴着结实的大钻戒用硬拳揍的
This had rings and knuckles.
别担心 我想了个B计划
Don't worry. I'm working on a plan "B."
或者应该说...
Or should I say...
-比伯计划 -不行
- Plan Bieber? - No.
别啊 我只是给他设计了个发型
No, I just gave him a little bit of a haircut.
-把孩子给我 我懂的 -好吧
- Give me the baby. I know. - Yes!
那是我行程中最好的部分
I mean, that's the great part of my schedule.
几乎每个夏天都能去趟欧洲
We make it to Europe almost every summer.
你们肯定也经常旅行吧
But I'm sure you guys travel.
说实话 我这15年去的地方
Well, honestly, I don't think I've been anywhere
基本就是儿童游乐场
without a water slide in 15 years.
真有意思
That's funny.
她提过埃斯特 道格
She's mentioned Esther, Dougie,
特里普 艾弗罗·乔迪
Tripp, Afro Judy...
但土杜这名字
The name "Tater"
她过去20年确实从没提过一次
has literally never even come up once in the last 20 years.
我一点都不奇怪
Oh, I don't know why I'm surprised.
我疯狂地爱了她四年
I was madly in love with her for four years...
可她从来对我视而不见
And I was basically invisible
直到某天我被炸土豆噎到她才注意到我
until the day I choked on that tater tot.
等等 我还以为你是她的旧爱呢
Wait. Uh, I-I thought you were her ex.
我倒是想
I wish.
菲尔 这周末你都在吗
Oh! So, Phil, are you here all weekend?
才不
No.
真遗憾 我还想推荐几项活动呢
Well, that's too bad. I was gonna suggest some activities.
朝圣者中心要举办
The Palmer Center is doing
印象派画家的回顾展
a wonderful retrospective of impressionists.
确实很遗憾
Oh. That is a shame.
那个领域我倒是挺有研究
That's a field I know quite a bit about.
菲尔 别丢人了
Phil. No.
从我身上能看出
Uh, you can see the influence, can't you,
早期模仿秀演员的神韵吧
of the, uh, early impressionists?
比如...
The, uh...
里奇·利特
Rich Little,
弗兰克·高辛
the Frank Gorshin,
再比如吉米·费伦节目上的
on the... Jimmy Fallon, if you will.
人家说的是画家
He meant the painter kind.
好吧
Yes.
-再来点喝的吗 -不了 没完呢
- Freshen your drink? - No. No, not done.
你是不是盼着我俩玩完呢
You'd know if I was finished with something,
才不会玩完呢
And I'm not.
-那就只有一杯咯 -是啊
- Just the one then. - Yeah.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
对不住 我在你前任面前让你难堪了吗
Sorry. Did I embarrass you in front of your ex-boyfriend?
我就知道
Yeah, I know about that.
我都告诉你了 你不会真吃醋吧
Because I told you. Come on. You can't seriously be jealous.
菲尔 都是20年前的事了
Phil, it was 20 years ago.
控制一下
Reign it in.
拜托啦 你让我觉得有点难堪了
Come on. You're embarrassing me a little.
行 但你能否认你之所以
Fine, but do you deny that part of the reason
想一个人来 部分原因就是为了那家伙吗
you wanted to come back here by yourself is that guy?
我觉得那不一定是坏事 克莱尔
I'm not even sure it's a bad thing, Claire.
人都会好奇自己没选的那条路通往何方
We all wonder about the paths we didn't follow,
你尽可放心大胆承认
But you could admit it.
我要是承认了 你可不准生气
Well, you can't be mad at me if I do admit it.
不会的
I won't.
我不是在承认
Well, I'm not... admitting it,
没有你的话我不会这么幸福
Because I couldn't be happier than I am in my life with you.
可是
But, mm...
我是说 或许
I mean... Maybe...
我略微想过 偷偷地瞄一眼
a tiny part of me just wanted to sort of peek through the window
那曾经可能会属于我的生活
and... see the life that might've been.
连个电梯都没有 爬楼累死老娘了
Never get tired of those three flights.
麦琪
Maggie!
跟大家打个招呼吧
Say hi to everyone.
等会儿 天使宝贝
In a second, angel.
老娘这一天过得不太顺
Mama's had a day.
我还以为那是卧室呢
Oh, I thought that was the bedroom.
这屋就是卧室 亲爱的
You're in the bedroom, honey...
也是客厅 书房
And the living room and the study
和健身房
and the gym.
可不管怎么说
Mm. But anyway...
听我说 不好意思失礼了
Listen to me. I'm being rude.
大家都好吧 家里怎么样啊
How is everybody? How's things?
-还不错 -其实
- Not too bad. - Actually...
不 我就是问 家里什么都有感觉如何
No, I'm literally asking you, how is it to have things?
噪音每天准点啊
Yep, right on schedule.
小声点 吵死了
Keep it down, ya hood rats!
麦琪 你当年也是个学生
Maggie, you were once a student.
我记得呢
I remember.
就是那时候上的这条一穷二白的贼船
That's when I boarded this little rocket ship to the moon.
菲尔 等会 谢谢你
Phil, wait. Thank you.
-谢什么 -感谢一切
- For what? - Everything.
真搞不懂那家伙怎么当上教授的
I'm not sure how that guy got to be a professor.
他蠢到什么份上才能甩了你啊
He'd have to be pretty stupid to dump you.
派对要开始了
Hey, the party's starting,
有个赏心悦目的大帅哥
and there's a really good-looking guy
我盼着跟他跳舞呢
I was hoping to do a little dancing with, so...
-你指我吗 -当然
- You mean me? - Yes.
等等 走之前
Wait. Before we go,
我想知道那里还有没有前男友
are there any more exes I should know about?
亲爱的 你把我想成什么了
Honey, what do you think I was like?
克莱尔·普里契特
Hey, Claire Pritchett!
斯特勒院长
Hey, Dean Stoller!
那只是段小情史
Super quick story.
还好 有时间实施C计划
All right, it's not too late for plan "C"--
放下宝宝我们就溜
We drop the baby and run.
什么 不行 你得跟她坦白
What? No. You have to tell her what you did.
你剃了人家孩子的头发
You scalped her baby.
我得把假发剪下来
I had to cut that wig off.
那你说怎么办
What did you expect me to do?
他不肯戴帽子
He keeps pulling his hat off.
你可以放着我来啊
Okay, well, you could've let me do it.
我接受过维达·沙宣的32小时美发训练
I have 32 hours of Vidal Sassoon training.
因为创意分歧我罢课了 住嘴吧
What? I left the program over creative differences. Shut up.
你们好
Hola!
-你好 -你好
- Hola! - Hola!
我得宝贝小天使
Oh! There's my little angel.
他怎么样啊
How was he?
说 说起来好笑
Uh... There--there's a funny story here.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
别管那宝贝
Forgot about that baby...
看看这个宝贝
And check out this one!
你打败了衣柜衣柜衣柜衣柜衣柜队吗
You beat closets, closets, closets, closets, closets?!
我们把他们打趴下了
We destroyed them!
是衣柜衣柜衣柜衣柜队
And it's closets, closets, closets, closets.
我说的是什么
What did I say?
我昨天教了你半个小时
We went through this for a half-hour yesterday.
别折磨我了
I can't do it again.
不 你去告诉她
Nope. You're gonna have to tell her.
什么 凭什么呀
What? Why?
她手上那两枚戒指跟凶器似的
Because she has two new rings.
一拳能刮掉我一块肉
That--that's gonna take the meat right off the bone.
小卡 只要你替我背黑锅
Okay, Cam, you take the fall for me,
我就陪你去密苏里州
And I will go with you to Missouri.
待一礼拜都行
I'll even go for a whole week.
十天
Make it ten days.
好吧
Okay, fine.
但我不希望周一见到的动物
But I don't want to meet anything on Monday
周五时成为我的盘中餐
that I'm gonna eat on Friday.
那是必然的
Oh, well, that's gonna happen.
我完美的小天使
Oh! My perfect angel!
交给你了 你最棒了
You got this. You're good.
歌洛莉亚 你还记不记得
You know, Gloria, do you remember
几个月前我把火锅借给你
that chafing dish I lent you a couple months back
你还给我时却有个缺口
that you returned with a chip in it?
每次卢克来
Every time that Luke comes over,
都会把阁楼里的东西翻出来
he takes things out of the attic and leaves them just...
到处乱放
everywhere!
是啊
Yeah.
你知道吗 有趣的是 那个火锅
Well, you know, funny thing about that chafing dish
是我祖母的 她是从...
is it was my grandmother's, and it was given to her--
卢克
Luke!
曼尼 看到你真是太好了
Oh, hey, Manny. Glad I ran into you.
听着 独唱的角色归你了
Listen, I'm gonna give you the solo.
真的吗 你肯定是听说了我今天的事
Really? You must've heard what happened to me today.
我现在很自信 我知道我可以
I feel confident now and I know I can do--
我才不在乎呢
Yeah, I don't care about ,any of that stuff.
我只需要你跟你妈说
I just need you to tell you mom
你给你弟弟乔剪了头发 好吗
that you gave your brother joe a haircut, okay?
没问题 能有多难看
No problem. How bad could it be?
总之 我听说你有一封信需要家长签名
Anyway, I heard you need a letter from school signed.
我的《独立宣言》仿制品做得可真了
I kinda nailed my declaration of independence replica.
用这支笔伪造了所有的签名
Forged every signature with this pen.
-那么 -不用多说了
- So... - Stop.
我们成交
We have a deal.
我说宝宝的头发是我剪的
I'll say I cut the baby's hair.
你这支神笔就归我
And you give me that cool pen.
-什么 我不是这意思 -就这么定了
- What? No. No, that's not what I was going to... - A deal's a deal.
莉莉 有小偷
A thief, Lily.
偷吃了我妈特地
That's who ate my last piece of cake
从哥伦比亚寄来的蛋糕的最后一块
that my mother send me specially from Colombia.
那蛋糕可以催母乳
It helps you make the milk.
这个奖杯真不错
Such a cool trophy.
那个新来的卢迪·索伦孙表现怎么样
Say, how'd that new guy Rudy Sorrenson do?
非常棒
He was great.
真有意思 他居然和以前的
It's funny how he has the same name
职业选手卢道夫·索伦孙同名
as one-time pro bowler Rudolph Sorrenson,
真是这样的话 可是违反联赛规则的
which would be against league rules.
我觉得挺有意思的
Well, I'd find it funny.
杰 快点 你得带孩子们去看电影
Jay, hurry up. You have to take the kids to the movie.
为什么宝宝还戴着帽子
And why does the baby still have that hat on?
他会热死的
He's going to burn up.
歌洛莉亚 有件事我要坦白
Gloria, I have a confession to make.
我给乔剪了头发
I gave Joe a haircut.
很难看
It's bad.
你为什么这样做
Why would you do that?
我小时候 我爸经常给我剪头发
My dad used to cut my hair when I was a kid,
我觉得这样可以增进我和宝宝间的感情
And I thought it'd be a nice way for the baby and me to bond.
但是我搞砸了
But I just made a mess of things...
我把一切都搞砸了
Like I... make a mess of everything.
我看看
Let me take a look at this.
-我的天 -太难看了
- Ay, dios mio! - Wow. It's really bad.
爸 你为什么要对亲生儿子下这种毒手
Dad, why would you do that to your own son?
他才这么小
He's just a baby.
而且你还偷吃蛋糕
Plus you ate that cake.
够了 别再怪他了
Okay, enough. Leave him alone.
他本来可以编些疯狂的谎话
He could have invented some crazy story,
但他却说了实话
but instead he decided to tell the truth.
家人就应该这样
That's what families do.
-是的 -对
- Yes, it is. - Right.
好了 快走吧
Okay, go. Go, go, go.
莉莉 宝贝 我们走了 快来
Lily, sweetie, we're leaving! Come on!
我知道他们都以为我会大发哥伦比亚式脾气
I know that they expected me to go all Colombian crazy.
但这又是一次机会 我让他们明白
But this was just another opportunity for me to show them
我不再是以前那个肤浅的歌洛莉亚
that I was not the superficial Gloria that I used to be.
而且 今天享受后我很放松
Plus I was very relaxed after the day I had.
你在哪里
Where are you?
在看医生 他在检查我的脚踝
At the doctor. He's checking my ankle.
怎样 你觉得我会把全天SPA享受就这样扔掉吗
What? Did you think I was gonna throw away a whole spa day?
妈妈来了 弗汉希欧
I'm coming, Fulgencio!
我为什么要这样做
Why am I doing this again?
老爸会很开心的
Dad'll get a kick out of it.
就像我们小时候那样 经常穿他的鞋子
Like when we were young and used to wear his shoes.
现在起来走几步
Now get up and take a few steps.
这是老爸要求的吗
Did dad ask for this?
不 不过他会喜欢的 跳下舞吧
No, but he'll love it. Maybe dance around.
好吧 跳起来
Okay, now jump.
这算哪门子的视频啊
What kind of video is this?
知道吗 我要上班了 抱歉
You know what? I've gotta go to work. I'm sorry.
谢了
Okay, thanks!
怎么不摔跟头了
What the hell?
终于摔了
Finally!